In the previous lesson, we were introduced
to
fluids and we learned about fluid
mechanics
and how it was separated into both fluid
statics
and fluid dynamics. One thing I want to
mention
about last video that I forgot to mention
is
that the units for density are in
kilograms.
Oops. They are in kilograms per
metres cubed.
Or kilograms per metres cubed.
Or if you're doing chemistry, which some
of
you might also be taking, it would be in
kilograms
because chemistry, usually you would use
grams
per decimetres cubed or grams per litre
would
also work because a decimetre cubed is
also
a litre. But we will be using kilograms
per
metre cubed. And pressure, they
are measured in either kilopascals or
atoms.
PA or, and this is just basically what
this
is, is it's the atmospheric pressure at
sea
level is one atom.
And kilopascals are another unit.
101, I believe, kilopascals is equal to
one
atmospheric pressure. Yeah.
And for IB, another good thing to know,
especially
for chemistry, is there are certain
conditions
where you will be doing your calculations.
This is standard temperature pressure
conditions.
And I'm telling you this because it's
pretty
useful to know ahead of time. Especially
if
you're like grade 9 or 10 and you haven't
been
introduced to the chemistry. So standard
temperature
pressure conditions are basically a set
unit
of conditions that you often use to make
your
calculations. And what this is, is
pressure
is equal to 100 kilopascals, or if you're
doing
AP, it would be one atmospheric pressure.
And temperature is zero degrees Celsius,
or
you could say 273.15 Kelvin if you like.
And yeah, basically these are a set of
conditions
that are really useful to know ahead of
time
because you're gonna have to use it
anyways
if you're going into IB, whether it's
physics
or chem, or maybe even mainstream as well.